Staff Researcher, Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology (SAIT)

■ sujin.steve.jang@gmail.com | 🗥 sujinjang.github.io | 🕿 Google Scholar

Resaerch Interests

My current and past research work broadly involve machine learning, human-computer interaction, visual analytics, and robotics. More recently, I am primarily interested in self-supervised learning, domain generalization, and cross-modal representation learning for computer vision tasks in the field of autonomous driving.

Work Experience

Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology (SAIT)

Suwon, South Korea

Staff Researcher

Jun 2020 - Present

Machine/Deep Learning for Visual Perception; Autonomous Driving; ADAS

S.LSI, Samsung Electronics Co.

Hwaseong, South Korea

Staff Engineer

Jan 2019 - Jun 2020

• Machine/Deep Learning for Visual Perception; Autonomous Driving; ADAS

Motorola Mobility LLC.

Chicago, IL, USA

Machine Learning Staff Researcher

Jun 2017 - Dec 2018

Machine/Deep learning; Computer vision; Augmented Reality(AR); Human activity analyses; Smart mobile/health devices

Education

Purdue University West Lafayette, IN, USA

Ph.D., in Mechanical Engineering

May 2017

- Specialization: Human-Computer Interaction, Visual Analytics, Machine Learning
- Thesis: Methods for Analyzing Natural Patterns and Physical Ergonomics of Human Gestures in Mid-Air Interaction
- · Committee members: Karthik Ramani, Niklas Elmqvist, David Ebert, Alexander Quinn, and Jitesh Panchal

University of Florida Gainesville, FL, USA

M.S., in Mechanical Engineering

Aug 2012

Aug 2010

- Specialization: Vision-based nonlinear estimation/control, Robotics, Machine Learning
- · Thesis: Experimental Demonstration of Structure Estimation of Moving Objects Using Unknown Input Observers
- Committee members: Carl D. Crane III, Warren E. Dixon, and Prabir Barooah

Kookmin University Seoul, South Korea

B.S., in Mechanical and Automotive Engineering

- Research intern at Unmanned Vehicle Lab.
- · Advisor: Jungha Kim

Publications

Journal Articles

- J.2 S. Jang*, A. Villanueva*, W. Stüerzlinger, S. Ambike, K. Ramani, "Advanced Modeling Method for Quantifying Cumulative Subjective Fatigue in Mid-Air Interaction", International Journal of Human-Computer Studies (IJHCS), Vol 169, Jan 2023 (*: equal contributions)
- J.1 S. Jang, N. Elmqvist, K. Ramani, "MotionFlow: Visual Abstraction and Aggregation of Sequential Patterns in Human Motion Tracking Data", IEEE Transaction on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG), vol 22. Jan 31, 2016 / IEEE VAST 2015 (22% acceptance rate).

Conference Proceedings (peer-reviewed)

- C.6 S. Jang, J. Na, D. Oh, "DaDA: Distortion-aware Domain Adaptation for Unsupervised Semantic Segmentation", Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS, Oral, 184/2665 ~ 6.9%), 2022
- C.5 S. Jang, W. Stuerzlinger, S. Ambike, K. Ramani, "Modeling Cumulative Arm Fatigue in Mid-Air Interaction based on Perceived Exertion and Kinetics of Arm Motion", In Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI), 2017 (25% acc. rate)
- C.4 C. Choi, A. Sinha, J. H. Choi, S. Jang, K. Ramani, "A Collaborative Filtering Approach to Real-Time Hand Pose Estimation", In Proceedings of the IEEE Interactional Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2015 (30% acceptance rate)
- C.3 S. Jang, N. Elmqvist, K. Ramani, "GestureAnalyzer: Visual Analytics for Pattern Analysis of Mid-Air Hand Gesture", In Proceedings of the ACM Symposium on Spatial User Interaction (SUI), 2014 (29% acceptance rate)

DECEMBER 12, 2022

- C.2 S. Gupta, **S. Jang**, K. Ramani, "PuppetX: A Framework for Gestural Interactions With User Constructed Playthings", In Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Advanced Visual Interfaces (AVI), 2014 (28% acceptance rate)
- C.1 **S. Jang**, A. P. Dani, C. D. Crane, W. E. Dixon, "Experimental Results for Moving Object Structure Estimation using an Unknown Input Observer Approach", In Proceedings of the ASME Conference on Dynamic Systems and Control (DSCC, Best Paper in Session Award), 2012

Patens

- P.2 N. A. Madhusudhana, V. K. Tyagi, N. Dabhi, H. Zhao, S. Jang, "Pressure sensing device interface representation", US Patent 11,320,984, 2022
- P.1 M. Qian, S. Jang, J. W. Nicholson, S. Wang, "Modifying an image based on identifying a feature", US Patent 11,023,769, 2021

Honors and Awards

- A.2 Magoon Excellence in Teaching Award, College of Engineering, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, 2015
- A.1 Best Paper in Session Award, ASME Dynamic Systems and Control Conference, Fort Lauderdale, FL, 2013

Teaching Experience

School of Mechanical Engineering, Purdue University

Graduate Teaching Assistant

West Lafayette, IN, USA Aug. 2013-May. 2016

ME 444: Computer-aided design and rapid prototyping

- · Course goals: generating and communicating design ideas, effective use of CAD tools for product design, action toy design
- · Instructed undergraduate students during the lab sessions and guided them to complete toy design projects

Media Coverage

- M.5 Health Hazards: Beware of 'gorilla arm syndrome, DECCAN CHRONICLE, June 23rd, 2017 (Article link)
- M.4 Arm and muscle fatigue accumulates during prolonged use of mid-air computer interfaces say Purdue University researchers, DATAQUEST, June 13th, 2017 (Article link)
- M.3 Researchers Study Gorilla Arm Fatigue in VR Gaming, VR Times, May 9th, 2017 (Article link)
- M.2 Study researches 'gorilla arm' fatigue in mid-air computer usage, Physics.org, May 9th, 2017 (Article link)
- M.1 **Do YOU suffer from 'gorilla arm'? Experts warn virtual reality controllers are leading to new medical problems**, DailyMail, May 9th, 2017 (Article link)

Scientific Community Service

- Reviewer, ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems [CHI], 2016–2021
- Reviewer, ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology [UIST], 2018
- Reviewer, ACM International Conference on Mobile Human-Computer Interaction [MobileCHI], 2019
- Reviewer, ACM Conference on Computer Supported Collaborative Work [CSCW], 2016–2019
- Reviewer, ACM Conference on Designing Interactive Systems [DIS], 2016–2017
- Reviewer, ACM Conference on Tangible, Embedded, and Embodied Interaction [TEI], 2017
- Reviewer, ACM Conference on Interaction Design and Children [IDC], 2017
- Reviewer, IEEE International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality [ISMAR], 2021
- Reviewer, IEEE Conference on Virtual Reality [VR], 2018–2019
- Reviewer, IEEE Symposium on 3D User Interfaces [3DUI], 2016
- Reviewer, IEEE Transaction on Visualization and Computer Graphics [TVCG], 2017
- Reviewer, IEEE Conference on Information Visualization [InfoVis], 2015
- Reviewer, IEEE Conference on Visual Analytics Science and Technology [VAST], 2016–2020
- Reviewer, EG/VGTC Conference on Data Visualization [EuroVis], 2016
- Student Volunteer, IEEE VIS, 2015

References

Available upon request

DECEMBER 12, 2022 2